A Guide to the Eugene Manlove Rhodes Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6316-b
Eugene Manlove Rhodes Collection 1936-1937
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6316-b
12 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1966 Apr 4
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to [William Gerard] Chapman, 1936 Oct 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Writes at the behest of Harry Herbert Knibbs regarding short stories written by Eugene Manlove Rhodes, her late husband; lists several that had been published in
    McClure's Magazine
    : "
    His Father's Flag
    , " "
    Beyond the Desert
    The Long Shift
    Ragged Twenty-Eighth
    Sealed Orders
    Line of Least Resistance
    "; in
    Red Book
    The Miracle
    The God from the Machine
    The Bird in the Bush
    The Brave Adventure
    The Enchanted Valley
    Pacific Monthly
    Lex Talionis
    " and "
    Bell the Cat
    Everybody's
    The Awaited Hour
    All Story
    On Velvet
    Neighbors
    An Interlude
    Wildcat Thompson
    The Fool's Heart
    , " as well as many in
    Out West
    apologizes for being unable to provides information on dates of publication and reprints.]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1936 Oct 28; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Indicates interest in those stories of Eugene Manlove Rhodes which are available for reprint; details his efforts to ascertain which ones are; states his intention to make on offer for second serial rights.]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1936 Nov 11; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Discusses serial rights and syndicate rights to 5 stories appearing in
    . "]
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to William Gerard Chapman, 1936 Nov 13; ALS, 3 p.
    [Indicates that Eugene Manlove Rhodes kept no records, but thinks "
    The Perfect Day
    " from
    McClure's
    was the only story syndicated; expresses hope that "
    " can be published as a book as its heroine is "our baby who died" and Rhodes wished to "preserve her little baby life"; agrees to sell the rights to 3 stories mentioned in previous letter.]
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to William Gerard Chapman, 1936 Nov 16; TL, 1 p.
    [States that the manuscript of "
    " is in California, and that she will obtain the typewritten copy if rights are obtained from
    mentions that the publication date of "
    " was April, 1917; intends to pursue "
    " proposition with Brandt and Brandt; mentions her departure the following day to Boston for eye surgery.]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1936 Nov 20; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Discusses continued efforts to obtain syndicating rights to the stories held by
    encourages her to pursue effort to interest Brandt and Brandt in ["
    "]; cites the success of other Civil War novels:
    Guns Along the Mohawk
    by Walter D. Edmonds,
    Long Remember
    and
    Arouse and Beware
    by MacKinlay Kantor as well as
    Gone With the Wind
    . ]
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to William Gerard Chapman, 1936 Dec 13; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for advice on publishing "
    " and for his concern about her eye surgery which was not entirely successful; mentions her efforts to get publication dates of the available stories.]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1936 Dec 15; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Comments on her surgery, his search for publication dates to stories, and his hope that "
    " will find a publisher.]
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to William Gerard Chapman, 1937 Jan 13; ALS, 4 p.
    [States that she had "rescued" "
    " from California and sent it to Brandt and Brandt with his comments; describes her continuing medical treatment and states that because of it she will not be able to type "
    " for him as planned.]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1937 Jan 15; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Wishes her well in finding a publisher for "
    " and continued improvement in her vision; states his opinion that "
    " is not suitable for present day magazines due to its length.]
  - Mary Davison Rhodes to William Gerard Chapman, 1937 Feb 4; ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses a letter from Mr. Brandt; expresses her lack of understanding of his "viewpoint"; states her intention to submit the story to Harcourt and Brace. ]
  - William Gerard Chapman to Mary Davison Rhodes, 1937 Feb 6; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [States his view that she would do well to send "
    " to Harcourt, Brace, and Company in spite of Carl Brandt's letter which he returns.]